<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Network - Tag - LIANSONG&#39;S Blog</title>
        <link>https://yeliansong.github.io/en/tags/network/</link>
        <description>Network - Tag - LIANSONG&#39;S Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>ylsccnu@hotmail.com (LIANSONG&#39;S Blog)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>ylsccnu@hotmail.com (LIANSONG&#39;S Blog)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 11:14:00 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yeliansong.github.io/en/tags/network/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Prometheus &#43; Grafana</title>
    <link>https://yeliansong.github.io/en/2020-11-07-prometheus--grafana/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 11:14:00 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://yeliansong.github.io/en/2020-11-07-prometheus--grafana/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[1. Background introduction 1.1 Prometheus The Chinese is Prometheus, just by hearing the name, I feel very fanciful, and it is a very powerful thing. Let me talk about the story of Prometheus, he is a figure in the myth of Athens, the legend is that he fabricated the human form, and Athena gave each human form a soul. Zeus forbids humans to use fire. Seeing that humans are in distress, this buddy stole fire from Apollo, so he offended Zeus.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Detailed explanation of HTTP</title>
    <link>https://yeliansong.github.io/en/2020-5-30-http-%E8%AF%A6%E8%A7%A3/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 15:14:00 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://yeliansong.github.io/en/2020-5-30-http-%E8%AF%A6%E8%A7%A3/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This summary may not cover all HTTP knowledge points, but it is just based on my own understanding, and then combined with online information to summarize.
1. What is HTTP HTTP (hypertext transport protocol), is the hypertext transfer protocol, text can be understood as characters, text, audio and video, etc. Hypertext is not a simple text file, but a more complex mixture of various files.
In fact, it is very easy to understand.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Nginx</title>
    <link>https://yeliansong.github.io/en/2020-05-25-nginx/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 11:14:00 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://yeliansong.github.io/en/2020-05-25-nginx/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[1. What is Nginx? From Google result, Nginx is a free, open-source, high-performance HTTP server and reverse proxy, as well as an IMAP/POP3 proxy server. Nginx is known for its high performance, stability, rich feature set, simple configuration, and low resource consumption. Nginx supports up to 50000 concurrent applications.
2. Forward And Reverse Proxy The forward proxy is a proxy server between the client and the target server. In order to obtain content from the original server, the client sends a request to the proxy server, and specifies the target server, after which the proxy transfers to the target server and returns the obtained content to the client.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
