<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Algorithms - Tag - LIANSONG&#39;S Blog</title>
        <link>https://yeliansong.github.io/en/tags/algorithms/</link>
        <description>Algorithms - Tag - LIANSONG&#39;S Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>ylsccnu@hotmail.com (LIANSONG&#39;S Blog)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>ylsccnu@hotmail.com (LIANSONG&#39;S Blog)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 11:19:00 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yeliansong.github.io/en/tags/algorithms/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>tree</title>
    <link>https://yeliansong.github.io/en/2020-11-02-%E6%A0%91/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 11:19:00 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://yeliansong.github.io/en/2020-11-02-%E6%A0%91/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[1. Concept When it comes to trees, we must first talk about linear structures and nonlinear structures. The meaning of the data structure is to construct a set of interrelated data models, and then cooperate with the algorithm to solve some time-consuming operations in the computer. Linear and nonlinear are two very important data models.
Linear structure: The relationship between data elements is one-to-one, and the data elements echo each other stack queue linear table array string Non-linear structure: the relationship between elements is not one-to-one, and each element may have a relationship with zero or more other data Two-dimensional array Multidimensional Arrays generalized table Tree picture So the concept of a tree is very clear.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>HashMap</title>
    <link>https://yeliansong.github.io/en/2020-05-07-hashmap/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 10:14:00 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://yeliansong.github.io/en/2020-05-07-hashmap/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[1. The background of HashMap In this part, we first introduce hash tables and hashes from the advantages and disadvantages of arrays and linked lists. Take a look at the characteristics of hash tables and hashes compared to the first two.
1.1 Advantages and disadvantages of arrays First look at the memory structure diagram of the array.
Looking at this picture, you should clearly see the characteristics, advantages and disadvantages of the array.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
